Lloyd: So now that you've finished
session one of unit one, it's
time to complete the relevant
section in the assessment booklet.
If you haven't already done so you
can access your assessment booklet
by clicking on the assessment link
on page five and saving that in a
suitable location on your computer.
Once you've saved the document you can
then open it and it will display, as you
can see, on the screen in front of you.
So unit one, Understand
the Principles of Coding.
There's some assessment guidance
at the top, I strongly advise
you to read through that.
It gives reference to the different
command verbs that you will be asked
when answering questions such as
"describe", "explain", which require
you to provide some good detail in your
answers and also "identify", "list"
and "define", which may be briefer and
for example, identify or list is what
it says you just list your responses.
But the key is to always remember
when it's asking you to describe
or explain, try to provide as much
detail as you can in your responses.
So once you've read through that, you
then need to scroll down, pop your
name at the top, and then you can
move on to the questions in section
one, which is coding languages.
So the learning objectives are at the
top, the place in the assessment and
also the location in the course materials
if you need to refer back to that.
You can also use the hints and tips,
which you can access by clicking on
the hints and tips link on page five
or the final page of each session and
that will assist you and give you some
idea of what you need to think about
when you're answering the questions.
So for question one it's asking you in
the box below, state the meaning of the
term coding and give an example of where
and why you would use a coding language.
So what does coding mean?
What does coding do and
where do you use it?
So, in what instances would
you use a coding language?
What would you use it to do?
For question two, this is an identify
question, so you just need to list
your response and it's asking you to
identify at least two different coding
languages that can be used to code.
So using your learning from the course
materials, I would also suggest doing
some additional research and look at the
different coding languages out there.
And as it's only asking for two,
but you can give two, but try
and give as many as you can.
For question three, it's asking you to
do a little research to find examples of
procedural and object-oriented languages.
So then in the box below state,
the difference between the two.
So making sure that you evidence
websites or any books that you
used, this is important as well.
If you use information from your
research in your response, you
must reference that information.
So you can't just use  a paragraph
or some information from a website as
your whole answer, you have to answer
the question in your own words, but
you can use elements to support your
answer that you will then reference.
So it's procedural and object-oriented.
So what is the difference?
So when is procedural  used?
When is object-oriented used?.
For question four, it's asking you again
to do a little research to find examples
of syntax used in coding languages
and using your research to help you
to define what is meant by syntax.
So what does syntax mean?
In the English language syntax means
one thing, but in relation to coding,
what does syntax mean in coding?
And again you could give some examples
of how syntax is used in coding.
And for question five, in the box
below list examples of technologies
in the home that use code to run.
So again, this is a list question,
so you just need to provide a
list of the different types of
technology that you would have within
your home, that use code to run.
So just look around within the house,
and think about the different things that
you use potentially on a daily basis or
all the time that require code to run.
So once you've done that you would
carry out a spelling and grammar check
on your responses, proofread through
to make sure you're happy with your
responses, then save the assessment
document and move on to session two.